Arizona Commission of Affairs Records, 1954-1976
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Commission of Affairs Records, 1954-1976
MS 554
Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs
The Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records contain correspondence, minutes, records of appropriation hearings, memos and other communications by this American Indian-led organization aimed at making recommendations to the governor and legislators in regards to issues faced by Arizona tribes.
1.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/ E-Mail: LBRY-askspcoll@email.arizona.edu
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
Established in 1953 by the Arizona Legislature, the Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs had as its original mission to study the condition of American Indian residing in the state. Comprised of 15 members, the Commission includes 7 Indian and 2 non-Indians appointed by the Governor, and 6 others approved according to their office within the state government. The Executive Director for the Commission is also appointed by the Governor. Starting in 1986, the Commission changed mission and became the State’s liaison with Indian tribes.
Scope and Content Note
About half of the documents are bound by year and include correspondence to tribal council members and state politicians like Senator Barry Goldwater. The records include administrative documents like memos, budgets and minutes from their annual meetings and documentation on appropriation hearings, a list of members appointed by Governor Pyle, and newspaper clippings.
Materials related to the Arizona Commission on Indian Affairs can be found in the Labriola Center (Inter Tribal Council of Arizona) and as part of the Arizona Collection (Charles F. Gritzner Papers) in the Arizona State University Libraries.at
Access Terms
Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs.
Arizona.
Indians of North America – Arizona – Government relations.
Indians of North America – Arizona – History.
Indians of North America – Legal status, laws, etc. – Arizona .
Indians of North America – Politics and government.
Container List
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Arizona Commission of Indian Affairs Records, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 5)